Rama Sapto Pamungkas

Ciracas, Jakarta Timur 13740 (+62)82113517836ramasapto.my.id

ramasapto@gmail.com

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience developing web and maintenance applications organization across a range of e-commerce, HRGS department, consulting IT.

The programming languages I am currently good at are GO, PHP and C#. Able to implement Clean Architecture, CQRS (.NET) and Unit Testing.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PT. Bukit Makmur Mandiri.

Jakarta

Backend Developer

August 2022-Present

- Develop and maintain data-centric web applications and service using ASP.NET, C#.NET, MS SQL, and Agile/SCRUM methodologies.
- Implemented Workflow Engine for sending data to SAP, Approval Task, and another runtask.
- Implemented an C# .Net with CQRS microservice REST API.
- Implemented event-driven Azure Service Bus for workflow engine and logging.
- Collaborate with Business Analysts, Users and UI/UX to collect requirements and provide implementation.
- Integrated 3rd Party API mekari Qontak, Traveloka, Privy, Sambaash, and Coupa.

PT. Otten Coffee Indonesia.

Jakarta

Backend Developer

June 2021 - Sep 2022

- Develop and maintain data-centric web applications, mobile applications and service using PHP Symfony, Golang, Agile/SCRUM methodologies.
- Implemented event-driven RabbitMQ for push notification firebase and sending Email.
- Worked closely with Frontend Engineers to develop pixel perfect User Interface.
- Implements 2 HTTP transports and gRPC for communication between frontend and backend services.
- Create payment integration through payment gateways (xendit, midtrans, akulaku, etc.).

PT. Klik Digital Sinergi

Jakarta

Backend Developer

Sep 2020 - June 2021

- Develop and maintain web applications and services using Golang, NextJS, ReactJS, PostgreSQL, and Agile/SCRUM methodologies.
- Create API with Golang and NextJS for consume API local Kubernetes
- Integrated API jenkins, Gitlab and Sonarqube.

EDUCATION

University of Pembangunan Nasional Veteran Jakarta

Jakarta July 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (concentration: Informatics),

(GPA: 3.46/4.0)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Programming Language : Golang, SQL, C# (.Net), Javascript, Html, PHP **Database :** MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL server, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch **Operating Systems and Environment :** Linux, Windows, and MacOs

Libraries, Tools, and Framework: Git, Bitbucket, Jenkins, RabbitMQ, Azure Service Bus, ReactJS, NextJS, Docker,

Kubernetes, Bootstrap, NodeJs, CSS, RFC, SAP, SonarQube